<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document xmlns="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0"
          xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
          xsi:schemaLocation="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0 http://maven.apache.org/xsd/xdoc-2.0.xsd">

    <properties>
        <title>Ferris Resiste</title>
        <author email="mjremijan@yahoo.com">Michael Remijan</author>
    </properties>

    <body>
        <section name="Configuration">
            <p>
                Configuring Resiste is not that difficult.  
                This page documents everything you need to do.
            </p>
        </section>
		
        <section name="JRE">
            <p>
                Resiste requires Java 8. The Windows and Linux downloads come embedded
                with a Java 8 JRE, so Resiste does not depend on the system-level JRE to run.  
            </p>
            <p>
                However, if you want to override the JRE that comes embedded
                with Resiste, you can do so by editing, in the <code>[RESISTE_HOME]/bin/</code>
                directory, the <code>start-resiste.sh</code> and <code>start-resiste.bat</code> 
                files.
            </p>            
        </section>
		
        <section name="Logging">
            <p>
                See the <a href="logging.html">Logging page</a> for more information
                about configuring logging.
            </p>
        </section>
		
        <section name="How to Send Email (SMTP Account)">
            <p>
                Resiste needs the SMTP information for your email provider. Each
                email provider is different so how you get this information is 
                up to you.  
            </p>
            <p>
                In the <code>[RESISTE_HOME]/conf/</code> directory, make a copy
                of <code>email(example).properties</code> as <code>email.properties</code>.
                Edit <code>email.properties</code>, adding your SMTP account
                details.
            </p>
            <source>
# 
# This file holds the information needed to access your email account.
# you should rename this file "email.properties" in order to get
# Resiste to find it.  If the "email.properties" file is not found when
# Resiste starts, the application will print an error message and exit.
#

# @SINCE 1.0.0.0
#  Value is either "true" or "false:
#  If "true" an SSL connection is used to connect to the SMTP server
#  If "false" an UN-ENCRYPTED connection is used to connect to the SMTP server
#
# @SINCE 1.1.9.0
#  Value is either "true" or "false:
#  If "true" an SSL connection is used to connect to the SMTP server
#  If "false" a TLS connection is used to connect to the SMTP server.
#
sslEnabled=true || false

# This is the name of the SMTP host machine.
host=smtp.somewhere.org

# This is the port number of the SMTP host machine.
# The same host may support both SSL and TLS but on
# different ports. So make sure your port number here
# matches with the 'sslEnabled' configuration above.
port=44

# This is what you use in the “username” field when
# you login. Typically this is the same as your email
# address, but this isn't always the case.
username=account

# This is what you use in the “password” field when
# you login. This value is CLEAR TEXT, so keep this
# properties file safe.
password=password

# This is the email address you want for the
# email's FROM field. Enter the value using
# the format shown below. Typically this is
# the email address for the account.
# WARNING: If you make this an email address other
# than the one for the account, the email may
# be immediately flagged as SPAM.
emailAddress=FIRSTNAME LASTNAME &lt;ADDRESS@EMAIL.COM&gt;

# This is the email address you want for the
# email's TO field. Enter the value using
# the format shown below.  For testing, it's a good 
# idea to send it to yourself first.
sendToAddress=FIRSTNAME LASTNAME &lt;ADDRESS@EMAIL.COM&gt;</source>            
        </section>
		
        <section name="RSS URLs to Watch">
            <p>
                Resiste will watch any RSS URL you configure.
                In the <code>[RESISTE_HOME]/conf/</code> directory, add your
                RSS URLs to <code>rss_urls.csv</code>.
            </p>
            <p>
                This is a simple comma-separated data file.  Here is an example:
            </p>
            <source>
aa312231-8510-422b-8f4d-18e7f4ae4405,https://xkcd.com/rss.xml</source>
            <p>
                Each line has 2 fields
            </p>            
            <ol>
                <li>ID</li>
                <li>URL</li>
            </ol>
            <p>
                <b>ID</b> can be any value you want, as long as it is unique.
                I suggest using an <a href="https://www.uuidgenerator.net/">Online UUID Generator Tool</a>
                to generate unique values.  But they can also be as simple as 1,2,3,4.
            </p>
            <p>
                <b>URL</b> is the URL of the RSS feed you want to keep track of.
                Typically, all you need to do is copy the link from your browser and
                paste it in.
            </p>
        </section>
        
        <section name="RSS Email">
            <p>
                <b>Configure RSS email subject</b> by editing, in the <code>[RESISTE_HOME]/conf/</code>
                directory, the <code>rss_email_subject.ftlt</code>.
            </p>
            <p>
                <b>Configure RSS email body</b> by editing, in the <code>[RESISTE_HOME]/conf/</code>
                directory, the <code>rss_email_body.ftlt</code>.
            </p>
        </section>
        
        <section name="Error Email">
            <p>
                <b>Configure error email subject</b> by editing, in the <code>[RESISTE_HOME]/conf/</code>
                directory, the <code>error_email_subject.ftlt</code>.
            </p>
            <p>
                <b>Configure error email body</b> by editing, in the <code>[RESISTE_HOME]/conf/</code>
                directory, the <code>error_email_body.ftlt</code>.
            </p>
        </section>	     
        
             
        <section name="Database location">
            <p>
                By default, Resiste will use a built-in Derby database to store
                the RSS history.  The built-in Derby database is located in
                <code>[RESISTE_HOME]/data/resiste</code>  
            </p>
            <p>
                In general, you never need to mess with this database.  However,
                if you want to move the Derby database somewhere else, you can
                configure this.  In the <code>[RESISTE_HOME]/conf/</code> directory, 
                configure the location of the Derby database by updating 
                <code>db.properties</code>.  
            </p>
            <p>
                Keep the <code>db.properties</code> file completely commented out
                to use the built-in Derby database. 
            </p>
            <p>
                Resiste only supports a Derby database at this time.
            </p>
            <p>
                <span style="font-weight:bold; color:red">NOTE:</span> See <a href="security.html" alt="security">security</a> for 
                information on encrypting the username and password.
            </p>
            <p>
                <b>LOCAL</b> Example
            </p>
            <source>
url=jdbc:derby:C:/Users/Mike/Documents/Databases/Derby/Ferris/resiste
username=resiste_standalone
password=x4A03HZ7ZV*lzB%
schema=APP</source> 
<p>
                <b>REMOTE</b> Example
            </p>
            <source>
url=jdbc:derby://localhost:1527/resiste
username=resiste_standalone
password=x4A03HZ7ZV*lzB%
schema=APP</source> 

          
            <p>
                Configuration complete! Next is <a href="security.html" alt="security">security</a>.
            </p>                              
        </section>  
    </body>
</document>